# IREM BAYRAK

# **UX** Designer

+49 173 217 3138

www.irembayrak.me
irembayrak1@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/irembayrak/

Berlin-based UX designer with 7 years of experience in finance. Eager to work in a team that values sharing knowledge, growing together, and bringing each other up and aims to create solutions to people's problems and use technology to make a better world.

### **Skills**

#### Design

UX Research
Information Architecture
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Testing
Visual Design
HTML & CSS

#### **Tools**

Sketch
Balsamiq
Zeplin
Invision
Figma

#### Languages

English German (B1) Turkish

### **Education**

#### Frontend Development for Designers

Career Foundry (June 2020 - Aug 2020)

Built my portfolio website (www.irembayrak.me) from scratch.

#### **Certified UX Design Course**

Career Foundry (Sep 2019 - June 2020)

Designed a responsive web app with mobile-first approach called PATI, a pet expert app.

#### Master of Science: Accounting and International Reporting

Bahcesehir University - Istanbul, Turkey (2015)

#### **Bachelor of Arts: International Relations**

TOBB University of Economics and Technology - Ankara, Turkey (2011)

## **Work Experience**

#### **Garanti BBVA**

Commercial Lending (June 2015 - Dec 2018)

Analyzed client's financial statements, annual reports to determine business, financial, operational, and industry risks, and facilitate the right credit decision.

Collaborated with marketing, legal, risk management, policy teams to include every stakeholder that will affect and be affected by the credit decision.

Monitored clients' business, financial data, and payment behavior to notice early warning signals and ensure the bank's NPL KPI target.

Involved in side projects such as developing and implementing an early warning system that enables us to identify risky business clients to reduce the probability of defaults.

#### Yapi Kredi Bank

#### **Seker Bank**

Underwriter (May 2014 - June 2015)

Underwriter (Apr 2012 - May 2014)

Prepared an underwriting report that covers the financial and business risks of commercial clients to share with the credit risk team to make the credit decision.

Collaborated with the credit policy team to improve the loan request and approval process and made recommendations.